FENIL PATEL

Full Stack Web Developer

Email: 7fenilpatel@gmail.com | Mobile: +1 (437) 986 6160 | Portfolio: fenil.me

GitHub: https://github.com/imfenil16 | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/imfenil16 |

Profile Summary

Passionate Full Stack Web Developer with more than 3 years of professional experience. On top of that, I have 4 years of Computer Science degree and 2 years of specialization in Web Designing and Development. I Mastered some important web development skills like SEO, UI/UX, and Responsiveness. Because of that, my recent website crossed 250K page views in just 45 days.

Experience

Full Stack Web Developer at Southerneast Inc.

Aug 2022 - Present

• Developed highly SEO-optimised websites using MERN stack and Strapi as a backend database. That resulted in the top position on google ranking for a few of them.

aitools.fyi

 This site crossed 250K page views and more than 40K unique visitors in 45 days. Ranked top on google among competitors due to this site sales almost doubled.

aioftheday.com

Built user authentication system using Next-auth and google as auth provide. Created user-appealing
UI for a smooth experience and easy-to-use Upstack functionality that involved working with RESTful
APIs for Posting user inputs and getting back users' old events.

Front-end Developer at Techmyntra Software Solution

May 2020 - June 2021

- Major duties were to code websites considering user experience with other important aspects like web accessibility and responsiveness and color contrasts.
- Almost all the sites were developed with React.js along with Java Script and Tailwind. Some applications were also built using Angular and TypeScript.

Skills

Programming Languages:- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JSX, Node.js, PHP, Python, Java, C, C#

Frameworks & Libraries:- React.js, Next.js, Angular, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, D3.js, GraphQL

Application Software:- VS code, WordPress, Code pen, GitHub, Figma, Canva, Adobe Photoshop, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook

Databases:- Strapi CMS, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, PostgreSQL, Sanity

Deployment:- Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, GitHub Pages

Other DevTools:- Google Tag Manager, Google Analytics, SEO, UI, UX, Chrome dev tools, Postman, NPM, Yarn, CMS, Git, Google Search Console

Dev Skills:- SEO, UI, UX, RESTful APIs, Sass Development, DOM Manipulation, React Hooks, State Management Libraries, JSON, Babel, Webpack, Static Site Generation, Server Site Regeneration

Education

Post-Graduation in Web Designing and Development Apr 2021 – Aug 2022 Conestoga College, Kitchener, Ontario, Canada CGPA:- 3.92

Related Courses:- Responsive Website Design, JavaScript Programming, Database Design & Maintenance, Application Development for Android, Website Security, Advanced Programming with .NET

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science June 2016 – Aug 2020 Aditya Silver Oak College of Engineering, Ahmedabad GPA:- 8.14/10

Related Courses:- Software Engineering, Object-oriented Programming, Database Management Systems, Mobile Application Development, Big Data Analytics, Data Mining, Operating System

Certifications

Triplebyte Certified Engineer

Aug 2022

Proficient level Triplebyte Front end Developer. Triplebyte is a job search platform with over 200,000 engines.

Machine Learning and Deep Learning Engineer from Softvan Pvt Ltd Jan 2019 – May 2019 Completed more than 150 hours of industry-level hands-on training on Artificial Intelligence. Which was partnered with Nvidia, AWS, and Silver oak University. Worked on a few projects like hospital chatbots, Human detection via camera, and Automatic turn On/Off lights.

Projects

aishot.me(Live Here)

 Tried and tested thousands of different prompts for generating desired styled Al Avatars(Prompt Hacking). Build MVP UI and worked on the automation part of collecting user images and storing them in Cloud storage.

buildweb3.dev(<u>Live Here</u>)

Creative and innovative design for showcasing Web3-related information like Crypto wallets, Web3
Podcasts, and Cryptocurrencies.

prexi.art(Live Here)

• Al Image generator using Banana.dev API and Stable Diffusion Image Generation Model. Artificial Intelligence Image Store with Eye-catching prototype and convenient download options for users.

Web3.0 Course Aggregator(<u>Live Demo</u>)

Web 3.0 Courses representation website for smooth onboarding of new members to the community.
 The app was developed using Next. is and Tailwind CSS with MongoDB as data storage.

onpageseocheck.com(Live Here)

 Vital SEO checking application for beginners. This site was built with the Server Side Generation feature of Next.js that helped fetch client requests in no time without a CORS issue. A famous data scrapping library cheerios was integrated for data extraction.

fenil.me(<u>Live Here</u>) ☐ My personal portfolio demonstrates my work, skills, and achievements. It's a simple Static site for high performance and with 100% SEO in the lighthouse test. Clean code practices and component division for easy understanding.